vendasta.com 2018-10-12

# Privacy policy | Vendasta

_Effective as of May 25, 2018_

Vendasta Technologies Inc. and its affiliates (“Vendasta”, “we”, “us”, “our”, or the “Company”) are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit our websites (“Websites”), individuals who access and/or use our software (“Platform and Solutions”), including our associated mobile applications owned and controlled by Vendasta (“Mobile Apps”). This Privacy Policy describes Vendasta’s privacy policy practices in relation to your access and uses of Platform and Solutions and its products and Mobile Apps (collectively, the “Services”), your use and access to our Websites and your choices regarding use, access, correction and deletion of your personal information. 

If you do not agree with the terms, do not access or use the Services and Websites or any other aspect of Vendasta’s business. 

By accepting this Privacy Policy, either by clicking a box indicating your acceptance, or by executing or electronically accepting an agreement that references this privacy policy, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

## Contents

  1. The Information We Collect
    1. a. When you visit our Websites
    2. b. When you visit our Platform and Solutions
    3. c. Import Option

  2. The Uses of Information Collected
    1. a. Your Profile
    2. b. Legitimate Interests under the GDPR
    3. c. Websites and Services
    4. d. Administration
    5. e. Marketing

  3. Disclosure to Third Party
    1. a. No Selling Of Your Personal Data
    2. b. Your Instruction
    3. c. Third Party Services/Marketplace Vendors
    4. d. Third Party Service Providers
    5. e. Mergers and Acquisitions
    6. f. Anonymized Data
    7. g. To Comply with Laws
  4. Navigational Information
    1. a. Cookies
    2. b. Log Files, IP Addresses
    3. c. Flash Cookies and Other Third Party Tracking
    4. d. Do Not Track
    5. e. Social Media Features and Single Sign On
    6. f. Link
  5. Correct, Update, Delete Information
  6.  International Transfer
  7. Security
  8. Age Limitation
  9. Public Forum, Refer a Contact, Customer Testimonial
  10. Mobile Apps
  11. Changes and Notices

## **1\. The Information We Collect** ****

### a. When you visit our Websites

When you come to visit our Websites, we collect information about your browser type, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, geographical location, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed (“Navigational Information”). Navigational Information is described in further detail below.

### b. When you visit our Platform and Solutions

When you request more information about the Services, we require you to provide the following personal information: your name, email address, your company name, and telephone number (“Primary Information”). 

When you purchase or subscribe to our Services, we require you to provide the following personal information: Primary Information, company address, billing name and address, the number of employees within the organization and any other information you choose to provide to us (“Personal Data”). 

### c. Import Option

Through our “import option”, we may also collect Personal Data or email addresses of contacts that you choose to share with us. When you provide us with personal information about your contacts, they are subject to your own privacy policy and you are responsible. We will only use this information for the specific manner under this Privacy Policy, such as to add new accounts to your Vendasta account. 

## **2\. The Uses of Information Collected**

### a. Your Profile

When you register with us, you create your own public profile and configure your own privacy settings. You can view your profile to verify what information you provide is being shared publicly and you can edit your profile to remove information you do not want to be displayed publicly. We may use information about you that we collect from other sources, including but not limited to newspapers and internet sources such as blogs, instant messaging services, Platform developers, social media websites and other users of our Websites, to supplement your profile.

### b. Legitimate Interests under the GDPR

To the extent that Vendasta’s processing of your Personal Data provided by you is subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) in the European Union (“EU”), Vendasta relies on its legitimate interests to process your data. This may include keeping your information after you deactivate your account for the period of time needed for us to pursue legitimate business interests, direct marketing purposes, conduct audits, comply with (and demonstrate compliance with) legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### c. Websites and Services

We use Navigational Information alone or in combinations with publicly available information about you to operate, enhance, improve and personalize your experience on our Websites. In addition, we use Navigational Information, Personal Data you have provided, publicly available information about you or in any combination of these to understand, operate, enhance, improve, research, and analyze the usage trends and preferences to the features of our Services and to create new features and functionality.

### d. Administration

We will use your email address or phone number to contact you for administrative purposes, for customer service purposes, to address intellectual property notice, to notify you of changes to our services, provide important notices, rights of privacy, or defamation issues. When you provide us with credit card information, we use it to check your financial qualifications and to collect payment from you. We use a third party service provider to manage credit card processing and we do not store any financial credit card information in our system. 

### e. Marketing

We may use your Personal Data to send information about new product features or marketing communications from the business of carefully selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you. These are third party marketing communications and you can control settings whether to receive them.

## **3\. Disclosure to Third Party**

### a. No Selling Of Your Personal Data

At Vendasta, we are not in the business of selling your information to any third party.

### b. Your Instruction

We will share, disclose, and update your Personal Data in accordance with your instructions, including any applicable Agreement, Terms of Conditions, and Terms of Use. 

### c. Third Party Services/Marketplace Vendors

When you access our Platform and Solutions, you will have access to purchase from third parties. For example, in our Marketplace, you are able to engage with third party companies or individuals as service providers (called “Vendors”) to process and support your business. When you enable a service or purchase a product with our Vendors, we may share some of your Personal Data. These third parties are not owned or controlled by Vendasta and they have their own sets of terms and conditions and privacy policies. Please refer to their privacy settings and notices of these Vendors. 

### d. Third Party Service Providers

We employ third party companies or individuals to provide service improvements or complimentary services. For example, we may employ third party companies or individuals for website creation and development, hosting, maintenance and support; virtual computing and storage services. These third party companies may have access to or process your information. For more information, click [here.](https://www.vendasta.com/privacy-policy/third-party-subprocessors)

### e. Mergers and Acquisitions

In the event that Vendasta is engaged in a  merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, financing, public offering of securities, sale of some or all of Vendasta’s assets or stock, acquisition of some or all of our business, a similar transaction or proceeding, or steps in contemplation of such activities, some or all Personal Data may be shared or transferred, subject to confidentiality agreements. 

### f. Anonymized Data

We may disclose or use aggregated or anonymized Data for any purposes including research. 

### g. To Comply with Laws

We may be compelled to disclose Personal Data if we reasonably believe such disclosure is to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others] in accordance with or required by any applicable law, regulation or legal process. 

## **4\. Navigational Information**

### a. Cookies

Cookies are small text files sent by us to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are unique to your account or your browser. Cookies can be used to recognize you and your preferences when you visit our Websites or Services and give you a personalized experience in a faster and more secure way. 

We use cookies and other ad technology such as Web beacons, pixels and tags or in any combination to compile information about your usage of our Websites or Services and give you a personalized experience in a faster and more secure way. They also help us market more effectively to users, provide aggregated auditing, research, and reporting. 

Session cookies are automatically deleted once the user closes the browser or Mobile App, whereas persistent cookies last until you or your browser deletes them, or they expire.

You may choose to disable this cookie feature in your browser. 

In addition, we use third party cookies like Google Analytics. For more information, click [here.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)

### b. Log Files, IP Addresses

As is true of most websites and technology services offered via internet, our servers automatically collect information when you access or use our Websites or Services and record them in log files. This information may include IP address, the address of the web address you have come from and you are going to, browser type and settings, your internet service provider or mobile carrier, your searches, your operating system, your location, the date and time you have accessed or used Services, information about your browser configuration and plugins, language preference and cookie data. 

### c. Flash Cookies and Other Third Party Tracking

Vendasta or our third party partners may use Flash cookies to remember settings, preferences and usage and volume information from you to provide personalized settings, enhanced interactions and more relevant communications, and to track the performance of our advertisements. 

### d. Do Not Track

Currently, the Company’s Websites or Services do not respond to your web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms. 

### e. Social Media Features and Single Sign On

The Company’s Websites and Services may use social media features, such as the Facebook “like” button. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Company’s Websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interaction with these features are governed by the privacy policy of such social media companies providing the relevant features. 

### f. Links

Our Websites may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. 

## **5\. Correct, Update, Delete Information**

Access and control over most Personal Data on our Websites and Services are readily available through the profile editing tools. Users of our Services may modify, export or delete any of their profile information at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deactivate their Services may do so. Deleted information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to members of the Services. 

We may correct, update, export, delete or otherwise modify any of the personal information that you have previously provided to us through the Company’s Websites and Services. 

## **6\. International Transfer**

By using our Services, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States. 

We may transfer Personal Data you provided to countries other than the one in which you live. The Company primarily stores your Personal Data in the United States. 

We offer EU Model Clauses to meet the adequacy and security measures for our customers that operate in the EU, and other international transfers of data. A copy of our standard Data Processing Addendum is found [here.](https://www.vendasta.com/privacy-policy/data-processing-addendum)

## **7.  Security**

At Vendasta, we take security of data seriously and is a priority. Our Websites and Services take appropriate precautions to protect Personal Data. Your account information is located on a secured server protected by identity and access management checks. All of our Services are served using Transport Layer Security (TLS) to protect data in transit, and all passwords are one-way hashed prior to storage to prevent discovery in the event of a data breach.

Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, we cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the internet or while stored on our system or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others. Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. 

## **8\. Age Limitation**

To the extent prohibited by applicable law, we do not allow use of Websites and Services by anyone younger than 18 years old. In the event that we learn we have collected personal information from anyone under the age of 18, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. 

## **9\. Public Forum, Refer a Contact, Customer Testimonials**

We may provide boards, blogs, or chat rooms on the Company’s Websites. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for any personal information you provide to these forums. 

You may elect to refer a friend by submitting a name and email address to us. We will send the contact a one-time email about Websites and Services and we do not store this information. 

We post customer testimonials and comments on our Websites, which may contain Personal Data. We obtain prior consent before we post any information our Websites. 

## **10\. Mobile Apps**

In addition to information we collect on our Websites and Services, when you use our Mobile Apps we may also collect further information including your city location, device model and version, device identifier (or “UDID”), OS version, and your subscription. We use mobile analytics software to better understand functionality of our apps on your mobile device. 

You may set your settings to receive push notifications and allow other access to your phone such as camera and contracts. 

Mobile Apps may transmit information to and from Devices to provide the Mobile Application services.

## **11.  Changes and Notices**

Vendasta reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time, in order to comply with laws, regulations, changes in our business, and changes in industry standards including security. Your use of our Services and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms and Conditions (click here), and our Terms of Use (click here).

If we make material changes, we will provide thirty (30) days notice via email, through the Services, or through mutually agreed channel of communication.

If you disagree with the changes or any part of this Privacy Policy, you should deactivate your Services account immediately and refrain from using our Services.
